[
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Physics involves the study of",
        "answer": "Nature & Natural Phenomena",
        "choices": [
            "Nature & Natural Phenomena",
            "Humans",
            "Birds & Animals",
            "Plants"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Classical Physics does not include subjects like",
        "answer": "Elementary Particles",
        "choices": [
            "Elementary Particles",
            "Mechanics",
            "Heat",
            "Sound"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Size of universe is of the order of",
        "answer": "10^26 m",
        "choices": [
            "10^26 m",
            "10^18 m",
            "10^40 m",
            "10^16 m"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Einstein was awarded Nobel Prize in Physics for",
        "answer": "Law of Photoelectric Effect",
        "choices": [
            "Law of Photoelectric Effect",
            "Theory of Relativity",
            "Law of Gravition",
            "Special Relativity"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Fundamental unit of luminous intensity",
        "answer": "Candela",
        "choices": [
            "Candela",
            "Watt",
            "Joule",
            "Lux"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Weber is derived unit of",
        "answer": "Magnetic Flux",
        "choices": [
            "Magnetic Flux",
            "Magnetic Moment",
            "Luminous Flux",
            "None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "The prefix femto stands for",
        "answer": "10^-15",
        "choices": [
            "10^-15",
            "10^15",
            "10^12",
            "10^-12"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Number of basic SI Unit is ",
        "answer": 7,
        "choices": [
            7,
            6,
            8,
            5
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Light-year is a unit of ",
        "answer": "Distance",
        "choices": [
            "Distance",
            "Light",
            "Intensity of Light",
            "Time"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Speed of light in a vacuum is approximately ",
        "answer": "3 x 10^8 m/s",
        "choices": [
            "3 x 10^8 m/s",
            "3 x 10^8 km/s",
            "3 x 10^6 m/s",
            "3 x 10^6 km/s"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Ampere is unit of",
        "answer": "Electric Current",
        "choices": [
            "Electric Current",
            "Electric Charge",
            "Magentic Flux",
            "Electric Resistance"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "SI unit of pressure",
        "answer": "Pascal",
        "choices": [
            "Pascal",
            "Dyne",
            "Newton",
            "Joule"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Decibel is unit of",
        "answer": "Intensity of Sound",
        "choices": [
            "Intensity of Sound",
            "Intensity of Light",
            "Speed of Light",
            "None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "SI unit of electric charge",
        "answer": "Coulomb",
        "choices": [
            "Coulomb",
            "Volts",
            "Ohm",
            "Ampere"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "One astronomical unit (AU) is the average distance between",
        "answer": "Earth & Sun",
        "choices": [
            "Earth & Sun",
            "Earth & Moon",
            "Sun & Moon",
            "Sun & Pluto"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Physical quantity without any unit",
        "answer": "Strain",
        "choices": [
            "Strain",
            "Stress",
            "Force",
            "Pressure"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "One Newton equals to",
        "answer": "1 Kg m/s^2",
        "choices": [
            "1 Kg m/s^2",
            "1 Kg m s",
            "1 Kg m/s",
            "1 Kg m s^2"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "SI unit of acceleration is",
        "answer": "m/s^2",
        "choices": [
            "m/s^2",
            "m/s",
            "ms",
            "ms^2"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "SI unit of electric resistance is",
        "answer": "Ohm",
        "choices": [
            "Ohm",
            "Ampere",
            "Volt",
            "Coulomb"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "1 kWh equals to",
        "answer": "3.6 x 10^6 J",
        "choices": [
            "3.6 x 10^6 J",
            "3.6 x 10^5 J",
            "3.6 x 10^-6 J",
            "3.6 x 10^-5 J"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Electric Potential is measured in",
        "answer": "Joule / Coulomb",
        "choices": [
            "Joule / Coulomb",
            "Watt",
            "Newton-second",
            "Joule"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which of the following pairs have the same units",
        "answer": "Work & Energy",
        "choices": [
            "Work & Energy",
            "Force & Pressure",
            "Power & Energy",
            "Force & Work"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Rate of change of momentum of a body is ",
        "answer": "Impulse",
        "choices": [
            "Impulse",
            "Energy",
            "Power",
            "Force"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "SI unit of power is",
        "answer": "Watt",
        "choices": [
            "Watt",
            "Joule-Second",
            "Joule",
            "Newton-Second"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which of the following equations represents Pressure in Physics",
        "answer": "Force / Area",
        "choices": [
            "Force / Area",
            "Force x Area",
            "Mass / Acceleration",
            "Mass x Acceleration"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which of the following is a scalar quantity",
        "answer": "Mass",
        "choices": [
            "Mass",
            "Momentum",
            "Weight",
            "Gravity"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "One horsepower is approximately equal to",
        "answer": "746 W",
        "choices": [
            "746 W",
            "647 W",
            "476 W",
            "764 W"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Molecular formula of Methyl Isocynate",
        "answer": "C2H3NO",
        "choices": [
            "C2H3NO",
            "C3H5NO",
            "C4H7NO",
            "C4H9NO"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Ore of Thorium",
        "answer": "Monzite",
        "choices": [
            "Monzite",
            "Pitchblende",
            "Carnotite",
            "Hematite"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Ore of Uranium",
        "answer": "Pitchblende",
        "choices": [
            "Pitchblende",
            "Monzite",
            "Thorite",
            "Hematite"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which of the following acids is secreted in the stomach",
        "answer": "Hydrochloric acid",
        "choices": [
            "Hydrochloric acid",
            "Sulphuric acid",
            "Nitric acid",
            "Phosphoric Acid"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "The meter used to measure the distance moved by the vehicle is known as",
        "answer": "Odometer",
        "choices": [
            "Odometer",
            "Ammeter",
            "Speedometer",
            "Chronometer"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Heat transfer that does not require a medium is called",
        "answer": "Radiation",
        "choices": [
            "Radiation",
            "Reflection",
            "Conduction",
            "Convection"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "What type of rock is formed from the cooling and solidification of lava",
        "answer": "Igneous",
        "choices": [
            "Igneous",
            "Sedimentary",
            "Metamorphic",
            "Crystal"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which of the following represents the suitable condition for the liquefaction of gases",
        "answer": "Low Temperature, High Pressure",
        "choices": [
            "Low Temperature, High Pressure",
            "Low Temperature, Low Pressure",
            "High Temperature, High Pressure",
            "High Temperature, Low Pressure"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which of the following is an Iron ore",
        "answer": "Limonite",
        "choices": [
            "Limonite",
            "Cinnabar",
            "Bauxite",
            "Pyrite"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which component of fertilizer is used for stimulating early growth",
        "answer": "Phosphorus",
        "choices": [
            "Phosphorus",
            "Nitrogen",
            "Potassium",
            "Oxygen"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which of the following are the constituents of a sodia acid fire extinguisher",
        "answer": "Dilute sulphuric acid and sodium bicarbonate solution",
        "choices": [
            "Dilute sulphuric acid and sodium bicarbonate solution",
            "Dilute sulphuric acid and sodium carbonate",
            "Concentrated sulphuric acid and sodium carbonate solution",
            "Concentrated sulphuric acid and aluminium suplhate"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which of the following bacterial diseases is called splenic fever",
        "answer": "Anthrax",
        "choices": [
            "Anthrax",
            "Typhoid",
            "Cholera",
            "None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which of the following radiation is used to get relief from body aches",
        "answer": "Infrared",
        "choices": [
            "Infrared",
            "UV",
            "Visible",
            "None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which one of the following is an example of melamine used for making floor tiles",
        "answer": "Thermosetting Plastics",
        "choices": [
            "Thermosetting Plastics",
            "Thermoplastics",
            "Polythene",
            "PVC"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which of the following is the first artificially prepared element",
        "answer": "Tc",
        "choices": [
            "Tc",
            "Te",
            "Th",
            "TI"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which of the following has a highly elongated elliptical orbit",
        "answer": "Comet",
        "choices": [
            "Comet",
            "Asteroid",
            "Meteorite",
            "Meteor"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which of the following is the fluid part of the blood",
        "answer": "Plasma",
        "choices": [
            "Plasma",
            "WBC",
            "RBC",
            "Platelets"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which of the following minerals occur in Minas Gerais province of Brazil",
        "answer": "Iron",
        "choices": [
            "Iron",
            "Bauxite",
            "Mica",
            "Coal"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which of the following is a non-contact force",
        "answer": "Magnetic",
        "choices": [
            "Magnetic",
            "Frictional",
            "Impact",
            "None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "What is the structural and functional unit of Life",
        "answer": "Cell",
        "choices": [
            "Cell",
            "Organ",
            "Tissue",
            "Organism"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which of the following, corundrum and cryolite are important ore",
        "answer": "Aluminium",
        "choices": [
            "Aluminium",
            "Silver",
            "Tin",
            "Iron"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which of the following is the resistance of wire",
        "answer": "R = V/I",
        "choices": [
            "R = V/I",
            "R = IV",
            "R = I/V",
            "I = R/V"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "What is the value of solar constant",
        "answer": "1.4 kW/m2",
        "choices": [
            "1.4 kW/m2",
            "1.6 kW/m2",
            "1.2 kW/m2",
            "1.8 kW/m2"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which of the following the chlorophyll in photosyntesis is used for",
        "answer": "Absorbing light",
        "choices": [
            "Absorbing light",
            "Reduction of CO2",
            "Breaking downs water molecules",
            "No Function"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which part of alimentary canal receives bile from the liver",
        "answer": "Small Intestine",
        "choices": [
            "Small Intestine",
            "Stomach",
            "Oesophagus",
            "Large Intestine"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "The process of breaking down organic matter by micro-organisms is called",
        "answer": "Decomposition",
        "choices": [
            "Decomposition",
            "Respiration",
            "Photosynthesis",
            "Fermentation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which of the following is a major cause of pollution",
        "answer": "Burning of Fossil Fuels",
        "choices": [
            "Burning of Fossil Fuels",
            "Disposal of Plastics",
            "Deforestation",
            "Execessive use of pesticides"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Who was the first to propose a model for the structure of an atom",
        "answer": "J J Thomson",
        "choices": [
            "J J Thomson",
            "E Goldstein",
            "Rutherford",
            "Neil Bohr"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "In the following which is fundamental physical quantitiy?",
        "answer": "Electric Current",
        "choices": [
            "Electric Current",
            "Force",
            "Velocity",
            "Work"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "At time of a short circuit, the current in the circuit",
        "answer": "increases heavily",
        "choices": [
            "increases heavily",
            "varies continously",
            "reduces substantially",
            "does not change"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Frequency is measured in",
        "answer": "Hertz",
        "choices": [
            "Hertz",
            "metre/second",
            "radian",
            "watt"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "What is measured in hertz?",
        "answer": "Frequency",
        "choices": [
            "Frequency",
            "Energy",
            "Heat",
            "Work"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Bolometer is used to measure",
        "answer": "Heat Radiations",
        "choices": [
            "Heat Radiations",
            "Frequency",
            "Velocity",
            "Wavelength"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "What is hearing frequency range of Human",
        "answer": "20Hz to 20kHz",
        "choices": [
            "20Hz to 20kHz",
            "2Hz to 20kHz",
            "2Hz to 20Hz",
            "2kHz to 20kHz"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Ohm-meter is unit of ",
        "answer": "Resistivity",
        "choices": [
            "Resistivity",
            "Resistance",
            "Charge",
            "Conductance"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Angstrom is a unit of ",
        "answer": "Wavelength",
        "choices": [
            "Wavelength",
            "Energy",
            "Frequency",
            "Velocity"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "1 Zepto is equal to",
        "answer": "10^-21",
        "choices": [
            "10^-21",
            "10^21",
            "10^-12",
            "10^12"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "One micron is equal to",
        "answer": "10^-6 m",
        "choices": [
            "10^-6 m",
            "10^6 m",
            "10^-3 m",
            "10^3 m"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "One picogram is equal to",
        "answer": "10^-12",
        "choices": [
            "10^-12",
            "10^-21",
            "10^-9",
            "10^-6"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "What is the unit of pressure?",
        "answer": "Newton / sq. meter",
        "choices": [
            "Newton / sq. meter",
            "Newton-meter",
            "Newton",
            "Newton/meter"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Magnetic field is a ",
        "answer": "Vector Quantity",
        "choices": [
            "Vector Quantity",
            "Scalar Quantity",
            "Dimensionless Quantity",
            "None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "What is Galvanometer used to measure",
        "answer": "Electric Current",
        "choices": [
            "Electric Current",
            "Electric Charge",
            "Electric Resistance",
            "Electric Potential"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which of the following is used to measure the intensity of earthquake?",
        "answer": "Mercalli Scale",
        "choices": [
            "Mercalli Scale",
            "Ritcher Scale",
            "Seismograph",
            "Accelerometer"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Hot-wire ammeters are used to measure",
        "answer": "both AC and DC",
        "choices": [
            "both AC and DC",
            "only DC",
            "only AC",
            "neither AC nor DC"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which instrument is used for measuring electric potential?",
        "answer": "Potentiometer",
        "choices": [
            "Potentiometer",
            "Ammeter",
            "Galvanometer",
            "Accelerometer"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "The device used to measure electric current is",
        "answer": "Ammeter",
        "choices": [
            "Ammeter",
            "Potentiometer",
            "Voltmeter",
            "Voltameter"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "The resistance of an ideal voltmeter is ",
        "answer": "infinite",
        "choices": [
            "infinite",
            "negative",
            "zero",
            "one"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which instrument is used to measure humidity",
        "answer": "Hygrometer",
        "choices": [
            "Hygrometer",
            "Hydrometer",
            "Pyrometer",
            "Lactometer"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Electroencephalogram (EEG) is used in monitoring",
        "answer": "Brain",
        "choices": [
            "Brain",
            "Heart",
            "Liver",
            "Kidney"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "For a satellite, escape velocity is 11km/s. If the satellite is launched at an angle of 60 degree with the vertical, then the escape velocity will be",
        "answer": "does not change",
        "choices": [
            "does not change",
            "increases",
            "decreases",
            "becomes zero"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "What is the law in which under the same conditions of temperature and pressure, equal volumes of all gases contain equal number of molecules?",
        "answer": "Avogadro's Law",
        "choices": [
            "Avogadro's Law",
            "Graham's Law",
            "Pascal's Law",
            "Coriolis Effect"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "A goalkeeper in a game of football pull his hands backwards after holding the ball shot at the goal. This enables the goalkeeper to",
        "answer": "decrease the rate of change of momentum",
        "choices": [
            "decrease the rate of change of momentum",
            "increase the force exerted by the ball on hands",
            "exert large force on the ball",
            "increases the score"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "When the stone is brought from the surface of the moon to the earth, then",
        "answer": "its weight will change, but mass will not change",
        "choices": [
            "its weight will change, but mass will not change",
            "it mass will change",
            "both weight and mass will change",
            "neither weight nor mass will change"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which of the following is not a vector quantity",
        "answer": "volume",
        "choices": [
            "volume",
            "velocity",
            "displacement",
            "force"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which of the following is not a vector quantity",
        "answer": "speed",
        "choices": [
            "speed",
            "velocity",
            "torque",
            "displacement"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which of the following is a scalar quantity",
        "answer": "Pressure",
        "choices": [
            "Pressure",
            "Force",
            "Acceleration",
            "Velocity"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Current density is",
        "answer": "a vector quantity",
        "choices": [
            "a vector quantity",
            "a scalar quantity",
            "Dimensionless Quantity",
            "None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "A sudden rise in the barometric height indicates",
        "answer": "extremely dry weather",
        "choices": [
            "extremely dry weather",
            "coming of storm or cyclone",
            "possibility of rain",
            "dry weather"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "The time period of a pendulum clock is ",
        "answer": "1 second",
        "choices": [
            "1 second",
            "2 seconds",
            "1 minute",
            "1 hour"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which physical quantity is represented by the ratio of momentum and velocity of the body?",
        "answer": "Mass",
        "choices": [
            "Mass",
            "velocity",
            "Acceleration",
            "Force"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which is the correct formula of acceleration?",
        "answer": "a = (v-u)/t",
        "choices": [
            "a = (v-u)/t",
            "a = u + vt",
            "a = (u + v )/t",
            "a = u + v/t"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Force is the product of ",
        "answer": "Mass & Acceleration",
        "choices": [
            "Mass & Acceleration",
            "Mass & Velocity",
            "Weight & Density",
            "Weight & Acceleration"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Ball bearings are used to convert static friction into",
        "answer": "rolling friction",
        "choices": [
            "rolling friction",
            "drag",
            "sliding friction",
            "torque"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Which of the following energy changes involves frictional force?",
        "answer": "Kinetic Energy to Heat Energy",
        "choices": [
            "Kinetic Energy to Heat Energy",
            "Chemical energy to Heat Energy",
            "Kinetic Energy to Electric Energy",
            "Potential Energy to Sound Energy"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Lenz's law is derived from the law of conservation of ",
        "answer": "Energy",
        "choices": [
            "Energy",
            "Charge",
            "Momentum",
            "Magnetism"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "If a feather, a rubber ball and a wooden ball are failing freely simultaneously from the same height in the vacuum then",
        "answer": "all three will reach the ground together",
        "choices": [
            "all three will reach the ground together",
            "the wooden ball will reach the ground first",
            "the rubber ball will reach the ground first",
            "the feather will reach the ground last"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "When a body falls freely towards the Earth, then its total energy",
        "answer": "remains constant",
        "choices": [
            "remains constant",
            "increases",
            "decreases",
            "becomes zero"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "A second pendulum is mounted in a rocket. Its period of oscillation decreases when the rocket",
        "answer": "moves up with uniform acceleration",
        "choices": [
            "moves up with uniform acceleration",
            "comes down with uniform acceleration",
            "moves round the earth in a geostationary orbit",
            "moves up with uniform velocity"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "For a body moving with constant speed in a horizontal circle, which of the following remains constant?",
        "answer": "Kinetic Energy",
        "choices": [
            "Kinetic Energy",
            "velocity",
            "Acceleration",
            "Centripetal Force"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "If the spinning speed of the earth increases, then the weight of the body at equator will",
        "answer": "decrease",
        "choices": [
            "decrease",
            "increase",
            "remains same",
            "be doubled"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "The time period of a pendulum",
        "answer": "depends on its length",
        "choices": [
            "depends on its length",
            "depends on the mass",
            "depends on time",
            "depends on temperature"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "You are standing in an elevator. The force exerted by your weight on the floor of the elevator",
        "answer": "will be zero when the lift comes down with an acceleration of 9.8m/s2",
        "choices": [
            "will be zero when the lift comes down with an acceleration of 9.8m/s2",
            "will be zero when the lift goes up with an acceleration of 9.8m/s2",
            "Zero when the lift moves in any direction with an acceleration of 9.8m/s2",
            "will not be affected by the change in the rate of acceleration of the lift"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "A bus is moving along a straight path and takes a sharp turn to the right side suddenly, the passengers in the bus will",
        "answer": "bent towards left side",
        "choices": [
            "bent towards left side",
            "bent towards right side",
            "fall in forward direction ",
            "fall in backward direction"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "A man pushes more weight on the Earth at",
        "answer": "standing position",
        "choices": [
            "standing position",
            "sitting position",
            "lying position",
            "sleeping position"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Environment is a composite state of",
        "answer": "All of these",
        "choices": [
            "All of these",
            "Biotic Factors",
            "Abiotic Factors",
            "Physiographic Factors"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "What is the thin layer of gases around the earth called?",
        "answer": "Atmosphere",
        "choices": [
            "Atmosphere",
            "Biosphere",
            "Hydroshpere",
            "Lithoshpere"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "The atmosphere is mainly heated by the ",
        "answer": "long-wave terrestrial radiation",
        "choices": [
            "long-wave terrestrial radiation",
            "short-wave solar radiation",
            "volcanic emission",
            "emission from distant stars"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Air is a/an",
        "answer": "Mixture",
        "choices": [
            "Mixture",
            "Compound",
            "Element",
            "Electrolyte"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "The highest percentage of gas in the air is",
        "answer": "Nitrogen",
        "choices": [
            "Nitrogen",
            "Hydrogen",
            "Oxygen",
            "Carbon Dioxide"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "The tallest known living tree",
        "answer": "Sequoia",
        "choices": [
            "Sequoia",
            "Eucalyptus",
            "Deodar",
            "Parnang"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "The major component of CNG is",
        "answer": "CH4",
        "choices": [
            "CH4",
            "N2",
            "CO2",
            "H2"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Pollutant emission gas in vehichle exhaust is mainly",
        "answer": "Carbon Monoxide",
        "choices": [
            "Carbon Monoxide",
            "Carbon Dioxide",
            "Nitrogen Oxide",
            "Marsh Gas"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "Inhalation of air polluted with Carbon Monoxide is dangerous because",
        "answer": "It combines with hemoglobin",
        "choices": [
            "It combines with hemoglobin",
            "it combines with oxygen in blood",
            "it removes water from the body and causes dehydration",
            "it causes coagulation of proteins in the body"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "The components of acid rain is/are",
        "answer": "HNO3 & H2SO4",
        "choices": [
            "HNO3 & H2SO4",
            "HNO3",
            "H2SO4",
            "CO2"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Science",
        "question": "The major and top source of oxygen in the atmosphere is",
        "answer": "Photosynthesis by oceanic phytoplanktons",
        "choices": [
            "Photosynthesis by oceanic phytoplanktons",
            "Photosynthesis by forest plants",
            "photosynthesis by grassland ecosystem",
            "photosynthesis be wtland algaes"
        ]
    }
]